No destiny
Blackthorn is a adventure, action, western film directed by Mateo Gil.
In Bolivia, Butch Cassidy (now calling himself James Blackthorn) pines for one last sight of home, an
adventure that aligns him with a young robber and makes the duo a target for gangs and lawmen alike.
James Blackthorn, played by Sam Shepard.
Ing. Eduardo Apodaca, played by Eduardo Noriega.
Mackinley, played by Stephen Rea.
Yana, played by Magaly Solier.
Young James, played by Nikolaj Coster-Waldau.
Sundance Kid, played by Pádraic Delaney.
Blackthorn is a 2011 Western film directed by Mateo Gil and
starring Sam Shepard, Eduardo Noriega, and Stephen Rea.
Written by Miguel Barros, the film is a fictional account of an aged Butch Cassidy living under the assumed
name James Blackthorn in a secluded village in Bolivia 20 years after his disappearance in 1908.
Blackthorn was filmed on location in La Paz, Potosí, and Uyuni in Bolivia.
Initially released in Spain on 1 July 2011, the film was released
theatrically in the United States on 7 October 2011.
The film explores themes of robbery, miner,
treachery, sundance kid, native peoples.